## **Ana-Louise Trinidad**

Email: anamtrinidad@outlook.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://ana3nity.github.io/social-impact-ux-portfolio/">https://ana3nity.github.io/social-impact-ux-portfolio/</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ana-louise-trinidad/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ana-louise-trinidad/</a>

> | Bay Area, CA | Phone: (408) 444-6771

I contribute my passion and User Experience skills to nonprofits and organizations for just causes. I desire to use technology to provide solutions for marginalized communities.

#### **Technical Skills**

**UX/UI Design Tools:** User Research, User Interviews, Problem Spotting, Critical Thinking, Site Maps, Affinity Diagrams, Storytelling, Empathy Development, Usability Testing, Visual Design

**Technical:** Figma, Notion, Trello, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Visual Studio Code. Atom

## **Projects**

#### Public Utility County Website Redesign | UC Berkeley UX/UI Bootcamp

The aim of this project was to improve the usability and findability of new house owning users to start a water service on the county's website

• Skills | Technologies Used: Stakeholder Interviews, User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis, User Experience Design (UI/UX), Interaction Design, Prototyping, Usability Testing

#### Nonprofit Website Redesign Group Project | UC Berkeley UX/UI Bootcamp

<u>Filipino Advocates for Justice</u> is a grassroots non-profit organization that aims to engage Filipinos in Alameda county in social and economic justice. The goal of this project was to redesign FAJ's website with a focus on improving the user task flow of finding mental health resources..

 Skills | Technologies Used: User Experience Design (UI/UX), Site Maps, Information Architecture, User Interviews, Usability Testing, Survey Creation, Stakeholder Interviews, Teamwork Collaboration

**Locale App Group Project** | UC Berkeley *UX/UI Bootcamp* 

The aim of this project was to solve a wicked problem by improving visibility and accessibility of local resources to users who are out of touch with their local area form of a mobile app.

 Skills | Technologies Used: User Research (Interviews + Surveys) and Analysis, formation of research objectives & research plan, Survey Creation, User Interviews, Behavior Archetype, forming Problem Statement and How Might We Statement, Affinity Diagrams, Empathy Maps, Competitive Analysis, User Experience Design (UX-UI), Usability Testing, Teamwork collaboration

## **Work Experience**

### Filipino Advocates for Justice

April 2022 - Present

Domestic Worker/Caregiver Outreach for Filipino Advocates for Justice & UX designer & Wordpress Front-End Developer

- Creating social media outreach materials on Canva
- Re-making old outreach materials such as membership forms, outreach physical flyers using Word Doc and Canva
- Developing infographic and social media materials for internal Trainings and educational outreach

# Ohlone Community College Contact Tracer/Case Investigator for COVID-19

May 2021 - September 2021

- Conduct the initial investigation of possible exposures or positive COVID-19 cases and reports confirmed cases to Alameda Public Health Department and California Department of Public Health
- Develop training and presentation material and conduct trainings for faculty, staff, administrators and students on effective, contact tracing/case investigation

### **Volunteer**

## AAPI Women Lead Redesign Project User Researcher

April 2023 - Present

• User Research: Research Plan creation, User Survey creation, User interviewees, Affinity Diagram, Empathy Map, discovering User Persona, Stakeholder liaison, team management and collaboration

San Jose Peace and Justice Center Redesign & Develop Project User Researcher Lead & Wordpress Front-End Developer

March 2023 - Present

- User Research: Research Plan creation, distributed and recruited user interviewees via User Survey, conducted User interviewees, Affinity Diagram, Empathy Map, User Persona Creation, Site Map, Information Architecture, Stakeholder liaison, team management and collaboration
- Developed Mock-up with another Front-End Developer with HTML and CSS on Visual Studio Code
- Wordpress Front-End Developer: Implementation of High-Fidelity Prototypes

# San Jose Strong; Web Dev Committee & App Dev Committee April 2023 - Present User Researcher & Front-End Developer

- User Researcher:
  - Creation of Internal Database User Survey, Usability Testing Plan, Script, and Questions
- Web Dev Committee roles:
  - Assigned a portion of the website building-process using Webflow
  - Developing parts of the website from referencing High-Fidelity prototypes from the web designer
- App Dev Committee roles:
  - Helping with portion of the San Jose Strong app with Front-End coding such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, React
  - Contribute in making improvements to the app by usability testing

### **Education**

Certificate in UX/UI Design
University of California, Berkeley Extension

April 2023

Bachelor of Arts in General Biology San Francisco State University

May 2018